<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:48:11 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extended memory VM instances in OCI</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2023/09/21/extended-memory-vm-instances-in-oci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:48:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2023/09/21/extended-memory-vm-instances-in-oci/</guid>
      <description>While provisioning compute instances in OCI, you may come across scenarios which need more memory and cores than what the standard shapes provide. Extended memory VMs are meant to solve that problem. Such VMs are able to access cores and memory across a single physical socket and it allows them to go beyond the limits of standard shapes. There are no additional charges for using this specific feature. Customer is charged on the basis of total number of cores and total amount of memory used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can&amp;#8217;t su to oracle user</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2023/01/20/cant-su-to-oracle-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 16:55:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2023/01/20/cant-su-to-oracle-user/</guid>
      <description>Last week, got this issue reported by a DBA that he wasn’t able to su to oracle user from root on a Oracle Base Database VM in OCI. The login of opc user worked fine and he could do sudo su to root but he couldn’t su to oracle. When he did it just came back to root shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p7246/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 19:09:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p7246/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;wp-block-code&amp;#34;&amp;gt;``` select * from dual </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a new cell to Exadata with asm scoped security enabled</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2022/05/09/adding-a-new-cell-to-exadata-with-asm-scoped-security-enabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 13:26:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2022/05/09/adding-a-new-cell-to-exadata-with-asm-scoped-security-enabled/</guid>
      <description>A customer is using an Exadata X8M-2 machine with multiple VMs (hence multiple clusters). I was working on adding a new storage cell to the configuration. After creating griddisks on the new cell and updating cellip.ora on all the VMs, I noticed that none of the clusters was able to see the new griddisks. I checked the usual suspects like if asm_diskstring was set properly, private network subnet mask on new cell was same as the old ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smokescreen detects traffic from an Exadata VM</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2022/03/21/smokescreen-detects-traffic-from-an-exadata-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 19:30:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2022/03/21/smokescreen-detects-traffic-from-an-exadata-vm/</guid>
      <description>A customer who is using an Exadata X8M-2 with multiple VMs had Smokescreen deployed in their company recently and they reported an issue that one of the Smokescreen decoy servers in their DC was seeing traffic from one of the Exadata VMs on a certain port. That was rather confusing as that port was the database listener port on that VM and why would a VM with Oracle RAC deployed try to access any random IP on the listener port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to connect to the database with SQLPlus</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2022/01/06/unable-to-connect-to-the-database-with-sqlplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 18:41:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2022/01/06/unable-to-connect-to-the-database-with-sqlplus/</guid>
      <description>I was working on configuring a new database for backup to ZDLRA and hit this issue while testing a controlfile backup via Enterprise Manager -&amp;gt; Schedule backup. It could happen in any environment.
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;wp-block-code&amp;#34;&amp;gt;``` Unable to connect to the database with SQLPlus, either because the database is down or due to an environment issue such as incorrectly specified... If the database is up, check the database target monitoring properties and verify that the Oracle Home value is correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:07:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Delivered a presentation titled “An 18 pointers guide to setting up an Exadata machine” at an event organized by North India Chapter of All India Oracle Users Group in Gurgaon. Download it here. Delivered a presentation on GoldenGate basics at an event organized by North India Chapter of All India Oracle Users Group in Chandigarh. Download it here. Delivered a presentation on Exadata basics at Tech meet organized by All India Oracle Users Group in Noida.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File system already present at specified mount point /dbfs_direct</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/06/05/file-system-already-present-at-specified-mount-point-dbfs_direct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 20:19:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/06/05/file-system-already-present-at-specified-mount-point-dbfs_direct/</guid>
      <description>It was actually funny. So thought about posting it that sometimes how we can miss the absolute basics. This customer is using a virtualized Exadata with multiple VMs. One VM hosts the database meant to be used for dbfs and another VM connects to this DB over IB to mount dbfs file system using dbfs_client. One day VMs were rebooted and due to some reason the dbfs filesystem didn’t mount on startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database performance degradation due to multipath issues</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/03/22/database-performance-degradation-due-to-multipath-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 12:54:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/03/22/database-performance-degradation-due-to-multipath-issues/</guid>
      <description>To put it in bit of an Indian context, database is not your daughter-in-law that you can blame it for every performance issue that occurs in the environment. But it does happen. Most of the time it is the database that is blamed for all such issues. Many times, the issues are in some other layer like OS, network or storage.
Faced this issue recently at one of the customer sites where performance in one of the databases went down suddenly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZDLRA patching</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/03/12/zdlra-patching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 22:30:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/03/12/zdlra-patching/</guid>
      <description>To be honest, Fernando Simon has already documented all the steps needed in ZDLRA patching . So this post is more like a reference post for me and it points to the links on his blog. One thing he could change though are the post titles. He also agrees 😉
The RA library patching part can be considered of two different types. This is an important difference. Make sure that you follow the right set of commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[FATAL] [INS-44000] Passwordless SSH connectivity is not setup</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/03/10/fatal-ins-44000-passwordless-ssh-connectivity-is-not-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:17:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2021/03/10/fatal-ins-44000-passwordless-ssh-connectivity-is-not-setup/</guid>
      <description>Faced this while running installer for setting up a 2 node RAC setup (version 19.8) on an Oracle SuperCluster. The error reported in the log is:
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;From the error it appears that the ssh is not setup between two nodes but actually that is not the case. Here the error message is bit misleading. It turned out to be an issue with scp with openssh version 8.x. Running the setup with -debug option gives the clue: &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;wp-block-syntaxhighlighter-code &amp;#34;&amp;gt;``` &amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;protocol error: filename does not match request&amp;gt; Workaround is to pass the -T option to scp to ignore the new checks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing an Exadata mixed cells config with OEDA</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/10/27/doing-an-exadata-mixed-cells-config-with-oeda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 18:53:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/10/27/doing-an-exadata-mixed-cells-config-with-oeda/</guid>
      <description>Earlier versions of OEDA didn’t allow you to have mixed cells in the configuration i.e. High Capacity (HC) and Extreme Flash (EF). The way to deal with that configuration was that deploy the system with either HC or EF cells and then manually configure the remaining cells.
I am not sure when did it change but the newer versions allow you have mixed type of cells in a single OEDA configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing ZDLRA &amp;#8211; Part 2</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/10/06/implementing-zdlra-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 18:06:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/10/06/implementing-zdlra-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In part 1, we discussed few things that you should take care before implementation of a ZDLRA. In this post, we will discuss few more things that you should review before or at the time of implementation:
If you are getting two ZDLRAs (one each for primary and standby sites), there are two ways they can be deployed. One scenario is where all the primary databases (or the database that have no standby) backup to RA at the primary site and then the data is replicated from primary RA to RA at the standby site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRVF-4657 : Name resolution setup check for &amp;#8220;db-scan&amp;#8221; (IP address: x.x.x.101) failed</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/09/25/prvf-4657-name-resolution-setup-check-for-db-scan-ip-address-x-x-x-101-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 19:41:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/09/25/prvf-4657-name-resolution-setup-check-for-db-scan-ip-address-x-x-x-101-failed/</guid>
      <description>A quick note about an error I faced while running root.sh on an Exadata machine. The configuration tools failed with the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing ZDLRA &amp;#8211; Part 1</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/09/09/implementing-zdlra-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:33:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/09/09/implementing-zdlra-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Zero Data Loss Recovery Appliance (ZDLRA) is Oracle’s solution for database backups. It has many advantages over other backup solutions that are available in the market. This post has a brief introduction to ZDLRA and few links for further reading. This is a quick post about few of things that you should keep in mind if you are planning to get a ZDLRA (RA in short). Of course, there is a lot more that is needed while executing the whole plan, but these are some of the basics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Secure Fabric for network isolation in KVM environments on Exadata</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/07/17/using-secure-fabric-for-network-isolation-in-kvm-environments-on-exadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 21:21:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/07/17/using-secure-fabric-for-network-isolation-in-kvm-environments-on-exadata/</guid>
      <description>Exadata storage software version 20.1 introduces a new feature called “Secure Fabric” for KVM based multi cluster deployments (Exadata X8M). It enables network isolation between multiple tenants (i.e. KVM VMs based RAC clusters). This feature aligns with Infiniband Partitioning on OVM based systems. There are customers who in such scenarios want that VMs of one RAC shouldn’t be able to see traffic of the other RAC VMs. This feature achieves that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exadata Virtualized DB node restore</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/05/11/exadata-virtualized-db-node-restore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 21:31:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2020/05/11/exadata-virtualized-db-node-restore/</guid>
      <description>There are two common scenarios when we may need this:
An existing DB node has crashed and is unrecoverable (due to some failure and non-availability of any backups. Though some of the things may need to be done even if the backups were available). We have an existing Exadata rack that is virtualized. Now there is a new DB node and the existing clusters need to be extended to include the VMs on this new node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dbnodeupdate.sh appears to be stuck</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/12/21/dbnodeupdate-sh-appears-to-be-stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 06:37:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/12/21/dbnodeupdate-sh-appears-to-be-stuck/</guid>
      <description>I was patching an Exadata db node from 18.1.5.0.0.180506 to 19.3.2.0.0.191119. It had been more than an hour and dbnodeupdate.sh appeared to be stuck. Trying to ssh to the node was giving “connection refused” and the console had this output (some output removed for brevity):
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;wp-block-code&amp;#34;&amp;gt;``` [ 458.006444] upgrade[8876]: [642/676] (72%) installing exadata-sun-computenode-19.3.2.0.0.191119-1... &amp;lt;&amp;gt; [ 459.991449] upgrade[8876]: Created symlink /etc/systemd/system/multi-user.target.wants/exadata-iscsi-reconcile.service, pointing to /etc/systemd/system/exadata-iscsi-reconcile.service. [ 460.011466] upgrade[8876]: Looking for unit files in (higher priority first): [ 460.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AVDF installation error</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/12/05/avdf-installation-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 20:18:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/12/05/avdf-installation-error/</guid>
      <description>I was installing Database Firewall version 12.2.0.11.0 on a Dell x86 machine (with 5 * 500 GB local HDDs configured in RAID 10) and it got successfully installed. Later on, I came to know that this version doesn’t support host monitor functionality on Windows hosts. The latest version that supports that is 12.2.0.10.0. So that was the time to download and install 12.2.0.10.0. The installation started fine but it failed with an error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OGB Appreciation Day : Thank you community ! (#ThanksOGB)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/10/10/ogb-appreciation-day-thank-you-community-thanksogb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 19:40:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/10/10/ogb-appreciation-day-thank-you-community-thanksogb/</guid>
      <description>It was started by Tim Hall in 2016. This is a Thank you community post. There are so many experts posting on Oracle related forums, doing blog posts, sharing their scripts with everyone. All of you are doing a great job. I would like to mention three names especially:
Tim Hall : Tim is a legend ! I don’t consider something a new feature until Tim writes about it 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding grid disks in Exadata</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/02/18/understanding-grid-disks-in-exadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 18:37:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/02/18/understanding-grid-disks-in-exadata/</guid>
      <description>Use of Exadata storage cells seems to be a very poorly understood concept. A lot of people have confusions about how exactly ASM makes uses of disks from storage cells. Many folks assume there is some sort of RAID configured in the storage layer whereas there is nothing like that. I will try to explain some of the concepts in this post.
Let’s take an example of an Exadata quarter rack that has 2 db and 3 storage nodes (node means a server here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-04080: trigger &amp;#8216;PRICE_HISTORY_TRIGGERV1&amp;#8217; does not exist</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/01/22/ora-04080-trigger-price_history_triggerv1-does-not-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 19:15:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/01/22/ora-04080-trigger-price_history_triggerv1-does-not-exist/</guid>
      <description>It is actually a dumb one. I was disabling triggers in a schema and ran this SQL to generate the disable statements. (Example from here)
&amp;lsquo;ALTERTRIGGER&amp;rsquo;||TRIGGER_NAME||&amp;lsquo;DISABLE;&amp;rsquo; alter trigger PRICE_HISTORY_TRIGGERv1 disable;
HR@test&amp;gt; alter trigger PRICE_HISTORY_TRIGGERv1 disable; alter trigger PRICE_HISTORY_TRIGGERv1 disable * ERROR at line 1: ORA-04080: trigger &amp;lsquo;PRICE_HISTORY_TRIGGERV1&amp;rsquo; does not exist
HR@test&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;WTF ? It is there but the disable didn’t work. I was in hurry, tried to connect through SQL developer and disable and it worked !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error while running ggsci</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/01/12/error-while-running-ggsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 19:51:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/01/12/error-while-running-ggsci/</guid>
      <description>This was another issue that I faced while trying to configure GoldenGate in HA mode. ggsci was working fine after normal installation but after configuring it in HA mode and trying to run ggsci, it resulted in this:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;wp-block-preformatted&amp;#34;&amp;gt;[oragg@node2 product]$ ggsci&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Oracle GoldenGate Command Interpreter for Oracle&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Version 12.3.0.1.4 OGGCORE_12.3.0.1.0_PLATFORMS_180415.0359_FBO&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Linux, x64, 64bit (optimized), Oracle 12c on Apr 16 2018 00:53:30&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Operating system character set identified as UTF-8.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Copyright (C) 1995, 2018, Oracle and/or its affiliates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failed to execute the command &amp;#8220;&amp;#8221;/u01/app/xag/bin/clsecho&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/01/08/failed-to-execute-the-command-u01-app-xag-bin-clsecho/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 22:52:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2019/01/08/failed-to-execute-the-command-u01-app-xag-bin-clsecho/</guid>
      <description>I was configuring GoldenGate in HA mode by following this document. Everything worked ok but in the end while running agctl config goldengate to view the configuration of GoldenGate resource, it was failing with the following error:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;wp-block-preformatted&amp;#34;&amp;gt;[oracle@exadatadb02 ~]$ agctl config goldengate GG_TARGET&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Failed to execute the command &amp;#34;&amp;#34;/u01/app/xag/bin/clsecho&amp;#34; -p xag -f xag -m 5080 &amp;#34;GG_TARGET&amp;#34;&amp;#34; (rc=134), with the message:&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Oracle Clusterware infrastructure fatal error in clsecho.bin (OS PID 126367_140570897783808): Internal error (ID (:CLSB00107:)) - Error -1 &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;(ORA-08275) determining Oracle base&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; /u01/app/xag/bin/clsecho: line 45: 126367 Aborted (core dumped) ${CRS_HOME}/bin/clsecho.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dbca doesn&amp;#8217;t list diskgroups</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2018/12/26/dbca-doesnt-list-diskgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 21:01:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2018/12/26/dbca-doesnt-list-diskgroups/</guid>
      <description>This is an Exadata machine running GI version 18.3.0.0.180717 and DB version 12.1.0.2.180717. On one of the DB nodes while running dbca, it doesn’t list the diskgroups. it works fine on the other node.
I cheked the dbca trace and found that the kfod command was failing. I tried to run it manually and got the same error:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;wp-block-code&amp;#34;&amp;gt;``` [oracle@exadb01 ~]$ /u01/app/18.0.0.0/grid/bin/kfod op=groups verbose=true KFOD-00300: OCI error [-1] [OCI error] [Could not fetch details] [-105777048] KFOD-00105: Could not open pfile &amp;#39;init@.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New web based OEDA for Exadata</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2018/11/21/new-web-based-oeda-for-exadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:47:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2018/11/21/new-web-based-oeda-for-exadata/</guid>
      <description>It started with an xls sheet (that was called dbm configurator) . Then OEDA (Oracle Exadata Deployment Assistant) was introduced that was a Java based GUI tool to enter all the information needed to configure an Exadata machine. Now with the latest patch released in Oct, OEDA has changed again; to become a web based tool. It is deployed on WebLogic and comes with some new features as well. SuperCluster deployments will continue to use the Java based OEDA tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garbled display while running FMW installer on Linux</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/18/garbled-display-while-running-fmw-installer-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 16:26:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/18/garbled-display-while-running-fmw-installer-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>A colleague faced this while running FMW installer on a Linux machine. The display appeared like this
This thread gave a clue that it could have something to do with fonts. So I checked what all fonts related stuff was installed.
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: bash; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;[root@someserver ~]# rpm -aq |grep -i font stix-fonts-1.1.0-5.el7.noarch xorg-x11-font-utils-7.5-20.el7.x86_64 xorg-x11-fonts-cyrillic-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-ISO8859-1-75dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-ISO8859-9-100dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-ISO8859-9-75dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch libXfont-1.5.2-1.el7.x86_64 xorg-x11-fonts-ISO8859-14-100dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-ISO8859-1-100dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-75dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-ISO8859-2-100dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch libfontenc-1.1.3-3.el7.x86_64 xorg-x11-fonts-ethiopic-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-100dpi-7.5-9.el7.noarch xorg-x11-fonts-misc-7.5-9.el7.noarch fontpackages-filesystem-1.44-8.el7.noarch fontconfig-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>root.sh fails with CRS-2101:The OLR was formatted using version 3</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/18/root-sh-fails-with-crs-2101-the-olr-was-formatted-using-version-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 16:03:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/18/root-sh-fails-with-crs-2101-the-olr-was-formatted-using-version-3/</guid>
      <description>Got this while trying to install 11.2.0.4 RAC on Redhat Linux 7.2. root.sh fails with a message like
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;ohasd failed to start Failed to start the Clusterware. Last 20 lines of the alert log follow: 2017-11-09 15:43:37.883: [client(37246)]CRS-2101:The OLR was formatted using version 3. This is bug 18370031. Need to apply the patch before running root.sh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at Cloud day event of North India Chapter of AIOUG</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/06/presenting-at-cloud-day-event-of-north-india-chapter-of-aioug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 17:17:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/06/presenting-at-cloud-day-event-of-north-india-chapter-of-aioug/</guid>
      <description>I will be presenting a session titled “An 18 pointers guide to setting up an Exadata machine” at Cloud Day being organized by North India chapter of AIOUG. Vivek Sharma is doing multiple sessions on various cloud and performance related topics. You can register for the event here
https://www.meraevents.com/event/aioug-nic-cloud-day </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ksplice kernel updates and Exadata patching</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/05/ksplice-kernel-updates-and-exadata-patching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 23:02:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/05/ksplice-kernel-updates-and-exadata-patching/</guid>
      <description>If you have installed some one off ksplice fix for kernel on Exadata, remember to uninstall it before you do a kernel upgrade eg regular Exadata patching. As such fixes are kernel version specific so they may not work with the newer version of the kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-15040 ORA-15042 with EXTERNAL redundancy Diskgroup</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/03/ora-15040-ora-15042-with-external-redundancy-diskgroup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 23:27:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/11/03/ora-15040-ora-15042-with-external-redundancy-diskgroup/</guid>
      <description>A colleague was working on an ASM issue (Standalone one, Version 11.2.0.3 on AIX) at one of the customer sites. Later on, I also joined him. The issue was that the customer added few news disks to an existing diskgroup. Everything went well and the rebalance kicked in. After some time, something happened and all of a sudden the diskgroup was dismounted. While trying the mount the diskgroup again, it was giving</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p562/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 20:23:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p562/</guid>
      <description>[tweet] http://twitter.com/mohammedhanif/status/897402312817344512 [/tweet]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TNS-12543: TNS:destination host unreachable</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/07/15/tns-12543-tns-destination-host-unreachable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 10:23:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/07/15/tns-12543-tns-destination-host-unreachable/</guid>
      <description>Scenario : Setting up a physical standby from Exadata to a non-Exadata single instance. tnsping from standby to primary works fine but tnsping from primary to standby fails with:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;TNS-12543: TNS:destination host unreachable I am able to ssh standby from primary, can ping as well but tnsping doesn’t work. From the error description we can figure out that something is blocking the access. In this case it was iptables that was enabled on the standby server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-12154 in Data Guard environment</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/05/31/ora-12154-in-data-guard-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:24:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/05/31/ora-12154-in-data-guard-environment/</guid>
      <description>Hit this silly issue in one of the data guard environments today. Primary is a 2 node RAC running 11.2.0.4 and standby is also a 2 node RAC. Archive logs from node2 aren’t shipping and the error being reported is
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;ORA-12154: TNS:could not resolve the connect identifier specified We tried usual things like going to $TNS_ADMIN, checking the entry in tnsnames.ora and then also trying to connect using sqlplus sys@target as sysdba.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failed to create voting files on disk group RECOC1</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/04/28/failed-to-create-voting-files-on-disk-group-recoc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 14:31:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/04/28/failed-to-create-voting-files-on-disk-group-recoc1/</guid>
      <description>Long story short, faced this issue while running OneCommand for one Exadata system. The root.sh step (Initialize Cluster Software) was failing with the following error on the screen
Checking file root_dm01dbadm02.in.oracle.com_2017-04-27_18-13-27.log on node dm01dbadm02.somedomain.com
Error: Error running root scripts, please investigate…
Collecting diagnostics…
Errors occurred. Send /u01/onecommand/linux-x64/WorkDir/Diag-170427_181710.zip to Oracle to receive assistance.
Doesn’t make much sense. So let us check the log file of this step
2017-04-27 18:17:10,463 [INFO][ OCMDThread][ ClusterUtils:413] Checking file root_dm01dbadm02.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OneCommand Step 1 error</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/04/10/onecommand-step-1-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 22:20:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/04/10/onecommand-step-1-error/</guid>
      <description>Hit this silly issue while doing an Exadata deployment for a customer. Step 1 was giving the following error:
ERROR: 192.168.99.102 configured on dm01celadm01.example.com as dm01dbadm02 does not match expected value dm01dbadm02.example.com
I wasn’t able to make sense of it for quite some time until a colleague pointed out that the reverse lookup entries should be done for FQDN only. As it is clear in the above message reverse lookup of the IP 192.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle RAC 12.1 &amp;#8211; lsnodes exited with code 9</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/03/28/oracle-rac-12-1-lsnodes-exited-with-code-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 22:01:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2017/03/28/oracle-rac-12-1-lsnodes-exited-with-code-9/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to do a 2 node RAC setup on Solaris 11.3 where Oracle Solaris Cluster 4.3 was already configured. Installed was running but the Cluster Node Information screen was appearing like this
The install log shows this:
INFO: Checking cluster configuration details
INFO: Found Vendor Clusterware. Fetching Cluster Configuration
INFO: Executing [/tmp/OraInstall2017-03-28_12-50-48PM/ext/bin/lsnodes]
with environment variables {TERM=xterm, LC_COLLATE=, SHLVL=3, JAVA_HOME=, XFILESEARCHPATH=/usr/dt/app-defaults/%L/Dt, SSH_CLIENT=172.16.64.55 56370 22, LC_NUMERIC=, LC_MESSAGES=, MAIL=/var/mail/oracle, PWD=/export/software/grid/grid, XTERM_VERSION=XTerm(320), WINDOWID=2097165, LOGNAME=oracle, _=*50727*/export/software/grid/grid/install/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ERROR: SPFile in diskgroup &lt;&gt; does not match the specified spfile</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/09/20/error-spfile-in-diskgroup-does-not-match-the-specified-spfile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 22:12:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/09/20/error-spfile-in-diskgroup-does-not-match-the-specified-spfile/</guid>
      <description>Just a stupid error. Posting it so that someone else googling for the same thing can get a clue.
An ASM instance running with default parameters (no pfile, no spfile). Updated spfile for the instance with asmcmd spset command and bounced crs. After reboot also, it still wasn’t using spfile. Got puzzled and checked GPnP settings again. All looked good. Then in alert log came across this
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;ERROR: SPFile in diskgroup &amp;lt;&amp;gt; does not match the specified spfile +DATA/asm/asmparameterfile/registry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exadata &amp;#8211; grid disks, offset and resize operations</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p510/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 22:42:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p510/</guid>
      <description>On a freshly configured Exadata system the following command will give you the details of size and offset of each grid disk
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: plain; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;cellcli -e list griddisk attributes name,size,offset DBFS1_CD_00_celadm03 5G 32M --0.03125G DATA1_CD_00_celadm03 171G 5.03125G RECO1_CD_00_celadm03 14G 176.03125G So the First grid disk starts at offset 32M (0.03125G), its size is 5G and the next one starts at 5.03125G (0.03125G + 5G) and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>addNode.sh, failed root.sh and IB listener</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/09/13/addnode-sh-failed-root-sh-and-ib-listener/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 19:44:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/09/13/addnode-sh-failed-root-sh-and-ib-listener/</guid>
      <description>So this customer has an Exadata quarter rack and they have an IB listener configured on both DB nodes (for DB connections from a multi-racked Exalogic system). We were adding a new DB node to this rack. So just followed the standard procedure of creating users, directories etc on the new node, setting up ssh equivalence and running addNode.sh. All went fine but root.sh failed. Little looking into the logs revealed that it failed while running srvctl start listener –n &amp;lt;node_name&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OEDA&amp;ndash;Things to keep an eye on</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/09/08/oeda-things-to-keep-an-eye-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 15:44:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/09/08/oeda-things-to-keep-an-eye-on/</guid>
      <description>So if you are filling an OEDA for Exadata deployment there are few things you should take care of. Most of the screens are self explanatory but there are some bits where one should focus little more. I am running the Aug version of it and the screenshots below are from that version.
On the Define customer networks screen, the client network is the actual network where your data is going to flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-56841: Master Diskmon cannot connect to a CELL</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/05/19/ora-56841-master-diskmon-cannot-connect-to-a-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 22:15:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2016/05/19/ora-56841-master-diskmon-cannot-connect-to-a-cell/</guid>
      <description>Faced this error while querying v$asm_disk after adding new storage cell IPs to cellip.ora on DB nodes of an existing cluster on Exadata. Query ends with ORA-03113 end-of-file on communication channel and ORA-56841 is reported in $ORA_CRS_HOME/log/&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt;/diskmon/diskmon.log. Reason in my case was that the new cell was using different subnet for IB. It was pingable from the db nodes but querying v$asm_disk wasn’t working. Changing the subnet for IB on new cell to the one on existing cells fixed the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-01671 while creating cascaded standby from standby using RMAN DUPLICATE</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/12/19/ora-01671-while-creating-cascaded-standby-from-standby-using-rman-duplicate-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 20:50:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/12/19/ora-01671-while-creating-cascaded-standby-from-standby-using-rman-duplicate-2/</guid>
      <description>On a T5 Super Cluster (running 11.2.0.3) I was creating a cascaded standby from an already functional standby using RMAN DUPLICATE and it errored out with
ORA-01671: control file is a backup, cannot make a standby control file A quick search reveals that it is bug 11715084 that affects most of the 11.x versions except 11.2.0.4. There is a one off patch available for most of the versions or one can install the bundle patch that includes the fix for this patch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-01671 while creating cascaded standby from standby using RMAN DUPLICATE</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p466/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 19:38:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p466/</guid>
      <description>On a T5 Super Cluster (running 11.2.0.3) I was creating a cascaded standby from an already functional standby using RMAN DUPLICATE and it errored out with
ORA-01671: control file is a backup, cannot make a standby control file A quick search reveals that it is bug 11715084 that affects most of the 11.x versions except 11.2.0.4. There is a one off patch available for most of the versions or one can install the bundle patch that includes the fix for this patch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sangam 15</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/11/24/sangam-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 19:04:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/11/24/sangam-15/</guid>
      <description>This was my 6th year at Sangam and as always was good fun. We were a group of 4 people who were traveling from Delhi and we reached Hyderabad on Friday morning. Just wanted to keep a day for visiting Ramoji Film City and also wanted to avoid the rush that morning travel on the conference’s starting day brings. So after dropping the luggage at the hotel we hired a taxi and reached Ramoji Film City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRP process on standby stops with ORA-00600</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/08/20/mrp-process-on-standby-stops-with-ora-00600/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 14:33:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/08/20/mrp-process-on-standby-stops-with-ora-00600/</guid>
      <description>A rather not so great post about an ORA-00600 error i faced on a standby database. Environement was 11.2.0.3 on Sun Super Cluster machine. MRP process was hitting ORA-00600 while trying to apply a specific archive log.
The error message was something like this
MRP0: Background Media Recovery terminated with error 600 Errors in file /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0.3/diag/diag/rdbms/xxxprd/xxxprd1/trace/xxxprd1_pr00_6342.trc: ORA-00600: internal error code, arguments: &amp;lt;span style=&amp;#34;color: #ff0000;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;[2619]&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;, [539], [], [], [], [], [], [], [], [], [], [] Recovery interrupted!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing tips</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/05/19/writing-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 14:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/05/19/writing-tips/</guid>
      <description>Tim Hall has written some brilliant posts about getting going with writing (blogs, whitepapers etc). This post is the result of inspiration from there only. Tim says that just get started with whatever .
If you are into blogging and no so active or even if you aren’t you may want to take a look at all the posts to get some inspiration to document the knowledge you gain on day to day basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to learn Exadata ?</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/01/02/want-to-learn-exadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 14:49:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2015/01/02/want-to-learn-exadata/</guid>
      <description>Many people have asked me this question that how they can learn Exadata ? It starts sounding even more difficult as a lot of people don’t have access to Exadata environments. So thought about writing a small post on the same.
It actually is not as difficult as it sounds. There are a lot of really good resources available from where you can learn about Exadata architecture and the things that work differently from any non-Exadata platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VirtualBox and Windows driver verifier</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2014/12/03/virtualbox-and-windows-driver-verifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 16:04:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2014/12/03/virtualbox-and-windows-driver-verifier/</guid>
      <description>I was troubleshooting some Windows hangs on my Desktop system running Windows 8 and enabled driver verifier. Today when I tried to start VirtualBox it failed with this error message.
Failed to load VMMR0.r0 (VERR_LDR_MISMATCH_NATIVE)
Most of the online forums were asking to reinstall VirtualBox to fix the issue. But one of the thread mentioned that it was being caused by Windows Driver Verifier. I disabled it, restarted Windows and VirtualBox worked like a charm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle GoldenGate 11g Handbook</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2013/07/18/oracle-goldengate-11g-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:32:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2013/07/18/oracle-goldengate-11g-handbook/</guid>
      <description>Few months ago I contributed a chapter (on Monitoring, Troubleshooting and Performance tuning) to a GoldenGate book on Oracle Press that Robert Freeman was authoring. Thought of posting a small update that the book is now out. My name doesn’t appear on the main page but you will see it in the Acknowledgements section Below is a screenshot taken from Amazon preview .
You may want to grab a copy if you are using/planning to use Oracle GoldenGate 11g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle database 12c</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2013/06/27/oracle-database-12c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 07:28:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2013/06/27/oracle-database-12c/</guid>
      <description>So there is a new toy in the market for database geeks : Oracle has released database 12c. Every social platform is abuzz with the 12c activity. So thought that I should also complete the ritual In this post Aman has already summed up many important links.
Maria Colgan has posted some useful links here.
And here is a link to a slidedeck about Upgrading and Migrating to 12c.
Happy 12c’ing !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>agent deployment error in EM 12c</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2013/06/16/agent-deployment-error-in-em-12c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 22:34:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2013/06/16/agent-deployment-error-in-em-12c/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was configuring EM 12c for a Sun Super Cluster system. There were a total of 4 LDOMs where I needed to deploy the agent (Setup –&amp;gt; Add targets –&amp;gt; Add targets manually). Out of these 4 everything went fine for 2 LDOMs but for the other two it failed with an error message. It didn’t give much details on the EM screen but rather gave a message to try to secure/start the agent manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating to Exadata 11.2.3.1.1</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/08/19/updating-to-exadata-11-2-3-1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 22:37:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/08/19/updating-to-exadata-11-2-3-1-1/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note about change in the way the compute nodes are patched starting from version 11.2.3.1.1. For earlier versions Oracle provided the minimal pack for patching the compute nodes. Starting with version 11.2.3.1.1 Oracle has discontinued the minimal pack and the updates to compute nodes are done via Unbreakable Linux Network (ULN).
Now there are three ways to update the compute nodes:
1) You have internet access on the Compute nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-01422 while compiling objects</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/07/31/ora-01422-while-compiling-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 22:04:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/07/31/ora-01422-while-compiling-objects/</guid>
      <description>There was an interesting issue at one of the customer sites. Few tables in the database were altered and the dependent objects became invalid. But the attempts to compile the objects using utlrp.sql or manually were failing. In all the cases it was giving the same error:
SQL&amp;gt; alter function SCOTT.SOME_FUNCTION compile; alter function SCOTT.SOME_FUNCTION compile * ERROR at line 1: ORA-00604: error occurred at recursive SQL level 1 ORA-01422: exact fetch returns more than requested number of rows ORA-06512: at line 27 SQL&amp;gt; At first look it sounded like some issue with the dictionary as the error in case of every object (be it a view, function or package) was the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure GoldenGate Extract to read from remote logs</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/05/26/configure-goldengate-extract-to-read-from-remote-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2012 18:13:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/05/26/configure-goldengate-extract-to-read-from-remote-logs/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you may need to run GoldenGate on some different machine than the one that hosts the database. It is very much possible but some kind of restrictions apply. First is that the Endian order of both the systems should be same and the second is the bit width has to be same. For example it is not possible to run GoldenGate on a 32 bit system to read from a database that runs on some 64 bit platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning GoldenGate Extract Pump performance</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/05/25/tuning-goldengate-extract-pump-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 20:38:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2012/05/25/tuning-goldengate-extract-pump-performance/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note/post about the significance of COMPRESS and TCPBUFSIZE parameter in performance of a GoldenGate Extract Pump process. COMPRESS helps in compressing the outgoing blocks hence helping in better utilization of the bandwidth from source to target. GG is going to uncompress the blocks before writing them to the remote trail file on the target. Compression ratios of 4:1 or better can be achieved. Of course, use of COMPRESS may result in increased CPU usage on both the sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DML and HCC &amp;#8211; Exadata</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/12/22/dml-and-hcc-exadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:01:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/12/22/dml-and-hcc-exadata/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid Columnar Compression (HCC) is a new awesome feature in Exadata that helps in saving a lot of storage space in your environment. This whitepaper on Oracle website explains this feature in detail. Also Uwe Hesse has an excellent how to use all this post on his blog. You can see the compression levels one can achive by making use of HCC. It is very simple to use feature but one needs to be aware of few things before using HCC extensively as otherwise all your storage calculations may go weird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OGG-01004  Aborted grouped transaction on &lt;table_name&gt;&amp;#8216;, Database error 1403 ()</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/11/04/ogg-01004-aborted-grouped-transaction-on-database-error-1403/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 16:38:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/11/04/ogg-01004-aborted-grouped-transaction-on-database-error-1403/</guid>
      <description>The last post was just like that. It was this GoldenGate issue that woke me up from the deep sleep to do a post after a long time 😛 .
Well it was a simple schema to schema replication setup using GoldenGate. We were using the SCN method (Metalink Doc ID 1276058.1 &amp;amp; 1347191.1) to do the intial load so that there is no overlvapping of transactions and the replicat runs with minimum issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>expdp not consistent</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/11/04/expdp-not-consistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 15:10:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/11/04/expdp-not-consistent/</guid>
      <description>Came across this small oddity that documentation of 10.2 and 11.2 states that expdp by default takes consistent image of the database. But actually it is not so. You need to use flashback_scn/flashback_time for that. Metalink doc 377218.1 explains the scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dbc_min_pct and dbc_max_pct in HP-UX</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/05/25/dbc_min_pct-and-dbc_max_pct-in-hp-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 16:45:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/05/25/dbc_min_pct-and-dbc_max_pct-in-hp-ux/</guid>
      <description>It was a 10g (10.2.0.5 on HP-UX 11.23 RISC) database which was recently upgraded from 9.2.0.8. The CPU and memory utilization was going really high. After tuning few of the queries coming in top, CPU usage was coming within accetable limits but the memory usage was still high. There was a total of 16 GB of RAM on the server and the usage was above 90%, constantly. One of the reasons behind high usage was increase in the SGA size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-12547: TNS:lost contact</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/05/18/ora-12547-tns-lost-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 11:13:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/05/18/ora-12547-tns-lost-contact/</guid>
      <description>Very simple issue but took some amount of time in troubleshooting so thought about posting it here. May be it proves to be useful for someone.
Scenario was: Oracle is installed from “oracle” user and all runs well. There is a new OS user “test1” that also needs to use sqlplus. So granted the necessary permissions on ORACLE_HOME to test1. Tried to connect sqlplus scott/tiger@DB and yes it works. But while trying sqlplus scott/tiger it throws:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>waiting for resmgr:become active &amp;#8211; can&amp;#8217;t login</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/03/04/waiting-for-resmgr-become-active-cant-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 17:19:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/03/04/waiting-for-resmgr-become-active-cant-login/</guid>
      <description>Some time back, I was at a client where the customer complained that no one was able to log in to the database. It was Oracle 10.2.0.4 running on HP-Ux. I logged in to the database and checked the wait events:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; @wait EVENT COUNT(*) ---------------------------------------------------------------- ---------- wait for possible quiesce finish 1 Streams AQ: qmn coordinator idle wait 1 Streams AQ: qmn slave idle wait 1 Streams AQ: waiting for time management or cleanup tasks 1 SQL*Net message to client 1 smon timer 1 pmon timer 1 jobq slave wait 4 rdbms ipc message 11 SQL*Net message from client 27 resmgr:become active 322 11 rows selected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>waiting for resmgr:become active &amp;#8211; can&amp;#8217;t login</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p346/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 17:19:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p346/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues in upgrading from 9i to 10g</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/01/29/issues-in-upgrading-from-9i-to-10g/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 22:30:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2011/01/29/issues-in-upgrading-from-9i-to-10g/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had a chance to upgrade a 9.2.0.7 database to 10.2.0.5. The size of the database was around 800 GB. The major applications connecting to the database were developed in Pro*C and Oracle Forms. The upgrade itself pretty smooth but there were few glitches around that needed to be handled. Just thought about documenting all the issues:
These were few of the issues encountered, rest of the upgrade was super smooth !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-39083: Object type INDEX failed to create with error</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2010/12/04/ora-39083-object-type-index-failed-to-create-with-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 17:22:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2010/12/04/ora-39083-object-type-index-failed-to-create-with-error/</guid>
      <description>Another let-us-help-Google post ;).
While running impdp import in 11g, you hit:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;ORA-39083: Object type INDEX failed to create with error: ORA-14102: only one LOGGING or NOLOGGING clause may be specified It is related to bug 9015411 where DBMS_METADATA.GET_DDL creates incorrect create index statement by dumping both LOGGING and NO LOGGING clauses. Due to this the CREATE INDEX statement, while running impdp fails with the above error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EXP-00056: ORACLE error 28002 encountered</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2010/11/14/exp-00056-oracle-error-28002-encountered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 00:24:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2010/11/14/exp-00056-oracle-error-28002-encountered/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, a friend of mine asked me about an error he was getting while running a schema level export in Oracle 8i:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;exp system/manager@DB owner=ABC file=ABC.dmp log =ABC.log Export: Release 8.1.7.1.0 - Production on Fri Nov 12 04:21:05 2010 (c) Copyright 2000 Oracle Corporation. All rights reserved. EXP-00056: ORACLE error 28002 encountered ORA-28002: the password will expire within 11 days EXP-00056: ORACLE error 24309 encountered ORA-24309: already connected to a server EXP-00000: Export terminated unsuccessfully I googled and metalink’ed (oops…is there anything like that ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sangam 10</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2010/09/12/sangam-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 16:57:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2010/09/12/sangam-10/</guid>
      <description>It has been almost an year since i posted something (useful) here. The last post was also a crappy one 🙂 . Well, it all boils down to sheer laziness 😉 . Now, i think the time has come to be regular again. Here i am getting a good start talking about Sangam10, i attended last week. It was a great opportunity to meet so many fellow Oracle professionals and most awesomely to meet &amp;amp; see Jonathan Lewis talk about Performance &amp;amp; Tuning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delete Delete Faster Faster ;)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/10/08/delete-delete-faster-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 20:53:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/10/08/delete-delete-faster-faster/</guid>
      <description>2-3 days ago, I came across a code, intended to make delete faster. Just have a look 😉
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;. . . LOOP SELECT COUNT (1) INTO v_cnt FROM table1 WHERE ROWNUM &amp;lt; 2; IF v_cnt = 0 THEN EXIT; END IF; DELETE FROM table1 WHERE ROWNUM &amp;lt; 1000; COMMIT; v_cnt := 0; END LOOP; . . . </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wrap&amp;#8217;ed code and SQL trace</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/09/18/wraped-code-and-sql-trace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 21:42:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/09/18/wraped-code-and-sql-trace/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, one of my colleague asked that if he traced a wrap’ed PL/SQL procedure, would the SQL statements show up in the trace ? Very simple thing but at that moment i got, sort of into doubt. So i ran a simple test and yes they do show up 😉
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;CREATE OR REPLACE PROCEDURE wrap1 AS v_today DATE; BEGIN SELECT SYSDATE INTO v_today FROM DUAL; END; / C:\&amp;gt;wrap iname=wrap1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query parameter doesn&amp;#8217;t work with NETWORK_LINK in datapump import</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p256/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 22:46:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p256/</guid>
      <description>Today i was importing one table with datapump using NETWORK_LINK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query parameter doesn&amp;#8217;t wotk with Datapump import with NETWORK_LINK</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p255/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 22:36:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p255/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-30019: Illegal rollback Segment operation in Automatic Undo mode</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/07/09/ora-30019-illegal-rollback-segment-operation-in-automatic-undo-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 23:26:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/07/09/ora-30019-illegal-rollback-segment-operation-in-automatic-undo-mode/</guid>
      <description>Today i was refreshing a MVIEW (Oracle 9.2.0.1.0 on Windows 2000) and instead of writing
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;exec dbms_mview.refresh(&amp;#39;SCHEMA1.MVIEW1&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;C&amp;#39;); i wrote
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;exec dbms_mview.refresh(&amp;#39;SCHEMA1&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;MVIEW1&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;C&amp;#39;); And it gave me:
&amp;lt;span style=&amp;#34;font-family: Georgia; line-height: 19px; white-space: normal; font-size: 13px;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;which has nothing to do with the real error. Take care !&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATHER_SCHEMA_STATS &amp;#038; ORA-03001: unimplemented feature</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/07/08/gather_schema_stats-ora-03001-unimplemented-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 23:33:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/07/08/gather_schema_stats-ora-03001-unimplemented-feature/</guid>
      <description>Today i was gathering stats on one schema (10.2.0.3 on AIX 5.3, 64 bit) and it said:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: sql; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;ERROR at line 1: ORA-03001: unimplemented feature ORA-06512: at &amp;#34;SYS.DBMS_STATS&amp;#34;, line 13336 ORA-06512: at &amp;#34;SYS.DBMS_STATS&amp;#34;, line 13682 ORA-06512: at &amp;#34;SYS.DBMS_STATS&amp;#34;, line 13760 ORA-06512: at &amp;#34;SYS.DBMS_STATS&amp;#34;, line 13719 ORA-06512: at line 1 Little bit of searching on Metalink revealed that i had hit Bug no 6011068 which points to the base Bug 576661 which is related to function based indexes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBMS_SCHEDULER, DBMS_RLS and SYS_CONTEXT</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/06/19/dbms_scheduler-dbms_rls-and-sys_context/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 23:42:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/06/19/dbms_scheduler-dbms_rls-and-sys_context/</guid>
      <description>Today one of my colleague was working on development of a screen in Oracle Forms to give the end user an option to schedule a job using dbms_scheduler. With the hope that i would be able to explain it properly, the whole scenario is like this:
User will log in to the application with his username (Lets say USER01) and password (basically every application user is a database user). He is provided with a screen where he can enter details about the job and the code behind the button calls a PL/SQL procedure in the main application schema (lets say APP1) which in turn uses DBMS_SCHEDULER.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBMS_SCHEDULER, DBMS_RLS and SYS_CONTEXT</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p222/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 23:14:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p222/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take care of a slash in a SQL script</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/06/14/take-care-of-slash-sql-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 17:31:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/06/14/take-care-of-slash-sql-script/</guid>
      <description>Since long time i have almost been writing useless posts only. Now, i guess my blog doesn’t even look like an Oracle blog. So thought about posting something related to Oracle 😉
Day before yesterday a colleague at my workplace asked that she was running an SQL script (which contained a simple DBMS_MVIEW.REFRESH() statement to refresh an MVIEW), it ran successfully but after completion re-ran the last command run in the session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Required ;)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/02/23/required/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 23:42:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/02/23/required/</guid>
      <description>On the wall just outside my office. Who says there is recession ? 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote modified for S/W industry</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/02/22/quote-modified-for-sw-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 12:35:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2009/02/22/quote-modified-for-sw-industry/</guid>
      <description>Got this in a forward mail. Good one.
Forgiving or punishing
the terrorists
is left to God.
But,
fixing their appointment
with God
is our responsibility
– Indian Army
Updated statement for this in S/W INDUSTRY…
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
.
Forgiving or punishing
the Developer
is left to Manager.
But,
fixing their appointment
with Manager</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/contact-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 23:50:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/contact-me/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manually booting an OS from GRUB</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/12/14/manually-booting-an-os-from-grub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 19:28:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/12/14/manually-booting-an-os-from-grub/</guid>
      <description>One of my friend today asked me about removing Linux partitions &amp;amp; GRUB (from a dual boot system) and return back to windows alone. Removing Linux involves just formatting/removing the partitions. Now to remove GRUB either do fdisk /mbr from a Windows 98 bootable CD or do fixmbr after booting into repair mode with Windows XP CD. But if you have none then to remove GRUB you will need some utility like this one and if you reboot before doing that it might make GRUB unable to boot into Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My re-designed website ;)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/12/09/my-re-designed-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 20:39:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/12/09/my-re-designed-website/</guid>
      <description>Since long time i have been struggling to learn CSS and make my website look great. The efforts did succeed but not in a way i wanted. After playing with CSS for few months i finally switched to Joomla and yes, in a week my website looks pretty cool. CSS automated 😉 . Joomla installation is pretty next-next job. Then play around a bit and you are done. Next game is to choose a nice looking template according to your taste and addition of few extensions to make yours tasks easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>where 1=2 ;)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/12/06/where-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 12:58:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/12/06/where-12/</guid>
      <description>A small post to let everybody know that I am alive 😉 .
Few weeks back, in office we were looking at one procedure which was supposed to do a lot but if executed it finished in a sec (or less 😉 ). I started looking into it and just opened the procedure and started scrolling to find that the last line of the very first cursor read:
where 1=2;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTN forums suck ?</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/09/14/otn-forums-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 18:41:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/09/14/otn-forums-suck/</guid>
      <description>Okay, so kids have stopped crying as they got some milk from their mommy: forums are better now (than when came back after an upgrade). There are reasons that it takes time for the things to be smooth. Fine. But what drives me mad is the way Oracle handled this and now ? The font size and those bloody bullets on left side which tell you if you have read the post before ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTN forums &amp;#8211; 2nd upgrade attempt</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/08/28/otn-forums-2nd-upgrade-attempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 07:28:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/08/28/otn-forums-2nd-upgrade-attempt/</guid>
      <description>Well, as everybody has seen, last week they have again upgraded the OTN forums. And sadly it has been handled in a very poor manner. End result is that it is running terribly slow and throwing some errors many times. In my office, i cant even open it properly may be its too heavy or some issue with the internet. Also there has been lots of hues and cries about the new point system and all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lotus notes and sametime</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/08/20/lotus-notes-and-sametime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 23:00:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/08/20/lotus-notes-and-sametime/</guid>
      <description>My company uses Lotus Notes for email and Sametime connect as messenger for all the internal communication. Both are stupid applications and are a big resource hogs. Most of the systems are P IV with 512 MB RAM. You just run Lotus and Sametime 7 and it eats up everything. The system moves like a 386 based machine.
Moreover, i was looking for Lotus short cuts today and found that there is no short cut in Lotus for Send/Receive mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTN forums under maintenance</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/08/10/otn-forums-under-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 07:58:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/08/10/otn-forums-under-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>I was just wondering what kind of maintenance OTN forums are undergoing ? It is 2nd day today and still not available. I checked it yesterday morning and now today morning still under maintenance.
Is another new design on the way ? 😉
What you say !
Just noticed that there is an announcement about the maintenance in Community Feedback forum.
Due to maintenance, forums.oracle.com will be in read-only mode between 6pm PT, Aug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conducting my first interview ;)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/29/conducting-my-first-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 07:19:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/29/conducting-my-first-interview/</guid>
      <description>Last week i had a chance to conduct my life’s first interview. The guy was a DBA with 2 years of experience and it was supposed to be a telephonic call. I checked out his CV and wrote down around 8 questions on a paper, just to make sure that i myself don’t get confused during the interview 😉 . So i called him in the evening and started with introduction and his present job profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing outside DocumentRoot files in Apache HTTP server</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/22/accessing-outside-documentroot-files-in-apache-http-server-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 21:51:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/22/accessing-outside-documentroot-files-in-apache-http-server-2/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know a bit about Apache HTTP server but faced one issue in office…so thought about writing it here 😉
We are having a 3 tier setup where Oracle Application Server 10g was there on AIX 5.3. It runs Apache HTTP server and we needed to access the files outside DocumentRoot. A bit of googling revealed that we could use Alias for that. Basically we need to add the following small piece of text to httpd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBA_MVIEW_COMMENTS view in 10g</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/21/dba_mview_comments-view-in-10g/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 07:28:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/21/dba_mview_comments-view-in-10g/</guid>
      <description>Our application (3 tier, Front end Forms10g and back end 10gR2) provides user with a front end to refresh the mviews. That form has 2 columns showing mview name and the comment against it. Recently i saw that while opening this front end ORA-01403 NO DATA FOUND was being raised.
I opened the fmb and found that it was populating comments from DBA_TAB_COMMENTS. In 10g the comments against mviews are stored in DBA_MVIEW_COMMENTS unlike till 9i where it was in ALL_TAB_COMMENTS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to WordPress 2.6</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/15/upgrade-to-wordpress-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 22:28:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/15/upgrade-to-wordpress-26/</guid>
      <description>Just upgraded my blog to WordPress 2.6. There are few new things. This video from WordPress summarizes the new stuff:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commenting on my blog</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/08/commenting-on-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2008 23:28:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/07/08/commenting-on-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>Aman made me aware about not being able to post any comments on my blog. I checked and found that everything was fine with Firefox but in IE 6 it was not possible to post a comment. I was using Did You Pass Math plugin to stop comment spam and it had some problems in IE. I disabled it for the time being and installed WP-SpamFree. Everything seems to be fine except that it doesn’t allow very small comments and i haven’t been able to figure out where that setting is ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTN forums get a new look</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/06/29/otn-forums-get-a-new-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 20:25:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/06/29/otn-forums-get-a-new-look/</guid>
      <description>Just had a glimpse. OTN forums has got a new look. A bunch of new features has also been added. Some of the new things i noticed are:
That simple editor is now rich text editor. Also supports emoticons. You can add tags to a post and it displays the tag cloud (for all the posts) on right side. A post can be marked as a question and then there will be some points system based on answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Availability &amp;#8211; Live ;)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/06/28/high-availability-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2008 08:15:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/06/28/high-availability-live/</guid>
      <description>I just opened OTN forums and found:
High availability live 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A database &amp;#8211; one tablespace &amp;#038; one datafile</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/06/10/a-database-one-tablespace-one-datafile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 21:32:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/06/10/a-database-one-tablespace-one-datafile/</guid>
      <description>Today I was checking OTN forums and came across a thread. OP’s concern was:
One of the db i am supporting has about 3.3 Terabytes capacity and the application is using only 1 huge tablespace with one big file.
the system is linux 4 , 32 bit.
oracle version is 10.2.0.4
Is there a limit of space for a tablespace when you consider insert/delete/query performance?
Single datafile of 3.3 TB 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import and default values for columns</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/05/10/import-and-default-values-for-columns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 14:47:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/05/10/import-and-default-values-for-columns/</guid>
      <description>I had got an export of a database and had to import it to a new database. The only difference was that in new database few of the large tables were partitioned. So instead of partitioning it after the import, i thought about pre-creating the tables (with partitioning) and then run import with ignore=Y . Everything went fine. But later on the front end application gave some error and we came to know that default values for columns in some tables were not set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance&amp;#8230;is everywhere ;)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/22/maintenanceis-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 22:34:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/22/maintenanceis-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>I just opened the Oracle Community page and :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you searched &amp;#8220;%&amp;#8221; in metalink ?</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/18/have-you-searched-in-metalink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 20:43:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/18/have-you-searched-in-metalink/</guid>
      <description>Today I was searching for an error message in metalink and it was giving strange messages. Then i came to know that the error message contained “%” character and metalink was not really happy searching for it. Rather it showed a confusing message:
Pretty strange…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unxutils for Windows</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/10/unxutils-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 21:57:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/10/unxutils-for-windows/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating WordPress 2.5 upgrade</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/06/automating-wordpress-25-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 11:59:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/06/automating-wordpress-25-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>I recently upgraded my blog to WordPress 2.5. The manual process is real cumbersome. Today I came across few plugins which help in almost automating the upgrade stuff.
WordPress Automatic upgrade: As per description this plugin first takes backup and then upgrades. I didn’t try this one, though.
Instant Upgrade: I upgraded one of my blog using this. It doesn’t take care of backup but otherwise the upgrade was super smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTN forums etiquettes</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/04/otn-forums-etiquettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 07:09:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/04/04/otn-forums-etiquettes/</guid>
      <description>Finally finally finally a small sticky has been posted on OTN Database forums homepage. But its there only on Database forums page not on PL/SQL. It reads like:
Posters, please mind these common-sense rules when participating here:
– When asking a question, provide all the details that someone would need to answer it. Consulting documentation first is highly recommended. (See http://blogs.oracle.com/shay/2007/03/02 for more hints.)
– When answering a question, please be courteous; there are different levels of experience represented here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBAzine.com is back :)</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/31/dbazinecom-is-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 21:54:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/31/dbazinecom-is-back/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago i posted about DBAzine being down. I was just checking to see if its back.
Its rocking now.
Welcome back DBAzine.com 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to WordPress 2.5</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/30/upgrading-to-wordpress-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 17:46:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/30/upgrading-to-wordpress-25/</guid>
      <description>Just finished upgrading to WordPress 2.5. Everything seems to be working fine.
Another issue I just came to know that wherever i am using syntaxhighlighter to format the code, it doesn’t display properly in Internet Explorer. May be something to do with the plugin. Will try to fix it. It works fine in Mozilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade 10gR1 to 10gR2 &amp;#8211; DBUA error</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/27/upgrade-10gr1-to-10gr2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 22:53:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/27/upgrade-10gr1-to-10gr2/</guid>
      <description>Today I was upgrading 10gR1 to 10gR2 (10.2.0.1) on Linux x86. The upgrade went almost fine (except that I had to install one package and change few kernel parameters) but while running DBUA to upgrade databases, it gave an error:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: css; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Could not get database version from the Oracle Server component. The CEP file rdbmsup.sql does not provide the version directive and Start of root element expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EXP-00008: ORACLE error 600 encountered</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/24/exp-00008-oracle-error-600-encountered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 23:06:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/24/exp-00008-oracle-error-600-encountered/</guid>
      <description>Today I was running export of an Oracle 9.2.0.1 database. The export completed but with an ORA-600 error:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: css; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; EXP-00008: ORACLE error 600 encountered ORA-00600: internal error code, arguments: [xsoptloc2], [4], [4], [0], [], [], [], [] ORA-06512: in &amp;#34;SYS.DBMS_AW&amp;#34;, line 347 ORA-06512: in &amp;#34;SYS.DBMS_AW&amp;#34;, line 470 ORA-06512: in &amp;#34;SYS.DBMS_AW_EXP&amp;#34;, line 270 ORA-06512: in line 1 EXP-00083: The previous problem occurred when calling SYS.DBMS_AW_EXP.schema_info_exp I googled a bit and found that the problem is with applying some patchset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get rid of your copy paste woes in Windows</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/23/get-rid-of-your-copy-paste-woes-in-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 22:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/23/get-rid-of-your-copy-paste-woes-in-windows/</guid>
      <description>I was copying some data from a DVD and it stopped in between due to some error with some file. Then I was reminded of Total Copy (A small alternate utility to Windows copy) but even thats is not much stable and you have to right click &amp;amp; drag for copy/paste.
I googled a bit and came across another small utility called Tera Copy. Its just 1 MB download and replaces Windows copy/paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid state cooling for processors</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/23/solid-state-cooling-for-processors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 11:40:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/23/solid-state-cooling-for-processors/</guid>
      <description>Engineers Develop Solid-state Fan That Puts Traditional Coolers to Shame
Cool ! isn’t it ?
Soon we may be using 5 Ghz super cool processors in our desktop box 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dbazine.com has expired</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/22/dbazinecom-has-expired/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 15:45:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/22/dbazinecom-has-expired/</guid>
      <description>Today I was googling about Oracle Data Guard and came across an article on dbazine.com. I opened the link and it showed some stupid page. I checked again and again. Finally I noticed a message on top right:
dbazine.com expired on 03/13/2008 and is pending renewal or deletion.
🙁
It was a nice website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading data into Oracle from flat files</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p57/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 06:56:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p57/</guid>
      <description>This is a frequently asked question on almost all Oracle related forums (I see it many times, every week on OTN forums). SO thought about posting about some ways to load data into Oracle from flat files. There are three methods which we can use for this:
SQL Loader: The most common method used is using SQL Loader. It gives us lots of options. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Transactions in Oracle</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/04/autonomous-transactions-in-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 20:33:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/04/autonomous-transactions-in-oracle/</guid>
      <description>I came across a very nice post about Autonomous Transactions in Oracle written by Kevin Meade on orafaq. Thought about sharing the link.
His blog also has some very nice stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax highlighting for code in WordPress</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/03/syntax-highlighting-for-code-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 22:07:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/03/syntax-highlighting-for-code-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>I came across a post about syntax highlighting for code in WordPress on Thomas Roach’s blog who in turn saw it on Tyler Muth’s blog. There is a plugin called syntax highlighter which does all the beauty. Use is very simple:
Download it from here.
Upload to your blog’s plugins folder and extract it over there.
Now (on WordPress) go to Plugins page and activate the plugin.
To use it wrap your code like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing grants</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/03/missing-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 20:37:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/03/03/missing-grants/</guid>
      <description>Today one of my colleague was working on a simple PL/SQL procedure. Based on some logic it was returning count(*) from all_tab_columns for few tables. It gave count incorrectly for one table out of around fifty in total. He just hard coded the table name and ran it but again it showed count as zero.
Then he took the code out of procedure and wrote it in DECLARE, BEGIN, END and after running it showed the correct count.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/02/27/learning-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 21:29:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/02/27/learning-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>From Eddie’s blog I got a link to 3 posts on Regular Expressions on OTN written by CD. Wonderful stuff. Check out.
Part 1
Part 2
Part 3
&amp;amp; Thanks CD…wonderful work buddy !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-06502: PL/SQL: numeric or value error: host bind array too small</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 08:57:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p51/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was troubleshooting a PL/SQL procedure which was giving ORA-06502: PL/SQL: numeric or value error: host bind array too small. Another procedure was being called from within the first one. Finally after some struggle, I was able to find out that there was an insert [inserting to a table on a remote database (say B)] which was causing the whole trouble.
I ran the insert statement in SQL* Plus and it showed a trigger failing [on the table which was being inserted data into].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my new website &amp;#038; blog&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/02/06/welcome-to-my-new-website-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 20:42:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/02/06/welcome-to-my-new-website-blog/</guid>
      <description>Well, it was in my mind for some time, to register my domain name and finally its here 🙂 . I have imported all the posts from my blog on blogger. I will be checking and editing all the posts for any kind of issues with wordpress. If you see anything out of the way do let me know 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 08:01:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Amardeep Sidhu. I currently live and work in New Delhi, India. My main technology arena is Oracle on Windows &amp;amp; Unix platforms.
I did my B Tech in Computer Sci &amp;amp; Engg from Guru Nanak Dev University, Punjab, India. I started my first job in 2004 with Spice Telecom Pvt Ltd, a Mohali based GSM operator operating in Punjab.
I always had thought about programming in C/C++ but was met with Oracle in my first job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-01537: cannot add file &amp;#8211; file already part of database</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p48/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 20:37:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p48/</guid>
      <description>Today one of my friends called me to ask about ORA-01537: cannot add file ‘c:\test1.dbf’ – file already part of database. The simple reason for this could be that the datafile I am trying to add to a tablespace is already there. But no, in this case it was not like this. The tablespace was not there in DBA_TABLESPACES but the datafile was there in DBA_DATA_FILES and V$DATAFILE. Also the file has been physically deleted from the disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle from Dizwell&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/01/03/oracle-from-dizwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 22:41:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/01/03/oracle-from-dizwell/</guid>
      <description>Howard has posted a pdf on Oracle Administration on his new website. Do check out. Its awesome.
Update: Howard has shutdown his website, so unfortunately this pdf is not available.
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-03113 Refresh of a mview in Oracle 10g</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/01/03/ora-03113-refresh-of-a-mview-in-oracle-10g/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 07:33:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2008/01/03/ora-03113-refresh-of-a-mview-in-oracle-10g/</guid>
      <description>At my workplace we were facing a problem with refresh of a mview. Say it was created in schema of user1 but when I tried to refresh it from user2 it would give ORA-03113: end-of-file on communication channel. Then we raised a SR and have been following up with Oracle support for long but it was not getting anywhere. Yesterday that guy seemed to have reached some point. The mviews that we have created and are having problem with refresh are created on top of both local &amp;amp; remote objects and he said that up to 11gr2 there is no possibility of creating mviews on both local and remote objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trained in AIX&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/11/27/trained-in-aix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 20:56:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/11/27/trained-in-aix/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended a training on AIX system administration from IBM (organized by company, obviously 😉 It was a 7 days course covering all of the system administration stuff. There was a lot of new stuff to learn, LVM being the most number of times uttered word, once we did the chapter on LVM. It was a nice experience as a whole as for the first time I attended any training on Unix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle from Eddie Awad&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/11/27/oracle-from-eddie-awad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 20:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/11/27/oracle-from-eddie-awad/</guid>
      <description>Eddie Awad started a new series Oracle in 3 minutes on his blog. In the first post he has discussed about multi-versioning. Its a must watch for everyone who is working on Oracle. Hoping to get more of such stuff from Eddie.
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard&amp;#8217;s decision&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/23/howards-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 07:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/23/howards-decision/</guid>
      <description>Howard Rogers has done a post on his blog that is the site Dizwell worth it ? Do post your opinion. If he plans to close it down, we will miss a great resource for Oracle.
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking Tom ? Read this !</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/16/asking-tom-read-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 13:39:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/16/asking-tom-read-this/</guid>
      <description>Tom Kyte did a post on his blog about posting of reviews of questions on Asktom. In a nutshell the reviews not related to the original question will be ignored/deleted (not decided yet, as Tom said).
As other people said in the comments, personally I too like this idea very much. Earlier, many times, there were questions which started with someone asking about appropriate SGA size, then there were some other twists and discussions and then the thread ended in discussion about good or bad authors or something similar light years away from the original topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official Oracle wiki</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/15/official-oracle-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 21:12:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/15/official-oracle-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Today I was checking Eddie Awad’s blog. From there I came to know that Oracle has started Official Oracle Wiki hosted by Wetpaint. Check out. I just made my login. Hoping to contribute whatever little I can
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNDO tablespace in Oracle&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/09/undo-tablespace-in-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 19:44:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/10/09/undo-tablespace-in-oracle/</guid>
      <description>Today, I was following a thread on Oracle Forums. Someone asked a question about UNDO tablespace wrt to a scenario. The question was:
There is a database and its hot backup is taken on Friday. Now for Saturday, Sunday and Monday there are archive logs but no backups. Suppose the machine crashes on Monday. After we restore the database to Friday (from backup), recovery will happen. As UNDO tablespace is of Friday so it has no information related to transactions that happened on Saturday, Sunday and Monday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google friendliness of &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/09/19/google-friendliness-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 21:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/09/19/google-friendliness-of/</guid>
      <description>Being a new kid on the block, I think, my post will not fire any serious and “scary” discussion as it has happened many times in the past. Just writing my experience. Whenever I search something related to Oracle in Google there are few sites that are bound to come up in the very first results ( No surety about the relevance and completeness of the content, though). Today I was searching about scheduling new jobs in oracle and I was, sort of, surprised to see the results [Though, I got from there, what I was looking for &amp;amp; I would like to say Thanks for that].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning AWK&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/09/17/learning-awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 23:24:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/09/17/learning-awk/</guid>
      <description>I was searching for some good tutorials on awk. Found a very nice (brilliant indeed) article on Oracle website by Emmett Dulaney. A very good introduction for beginners. I searched for some other links as well. Have a read:
1. AWK: The Linux Administrators’ Wisdom Kit
2. A Guided Tour Of Awk
3. AWK Programming
4. UNIX Utilities – awk
Happy awk’ing 🙂
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing Wikipedia&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/09/16/tracing-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 23:23:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/09/16/tracing-wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>Today Stumble gave me a link to an article on a website. That article talks about a guy Virgil Griffith who wrote a piece of software to track IP addresses of the people, editing the Wikipedia content. Some really interesting things came up: Apple attacking Microsoft and then Microsoft taking revenge. Have a look at the full article. It makes an interesting read. Read more about this guy on Wikipedia here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being an Oracle trainer&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/19/being-an-oracle-trainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 15:31:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/19/being-an-oracle-trainer/</guid>
      <description>Few days back, I had to give Oracle DBA training to a group of about 20-25 semi-technical people (Semi-technical, because most of them were not really DBA kinda folks doing all the techie stuff with Oracle, but in-fact having learned some bits &amp;amp; bytes of Oracle sometime back and these days looking into application functionality from technical perspective). I, having just about 10 months of experience with DBA profile, had to cover, everything about Oracle starting from creating database and up to performance tuning 🙂 Its really an interesting job if the audience is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing a full database&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/18/importing-a-full-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 18:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/18/importing-a-full-database/</guid>
      <description>Many times, we are required to restore a database from an export dmp file. Its a simple task but sometimes there are some issues left like invalid objects or some objects missing, in the newly created database. Following steps, followed in order can help in creating an error free database:
Create a blank database: The very first step is to create a blank database which is to be used as the target database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle 11g&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/13/oracle-11g/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 22:25:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/13/oracle-11g/</guid>
      <description>The day when Oracle 11g was made available for download on OTN, there was sort of, flood of posts in the Oracle blogsphere. Here is a quick recap of few of the posts (Whatsoever I could find through OraNA and my Netvibes)
Eddie Awad about 11g, I think he was the first one to post
Then Doug Burns here
Howard on installing 11g
Another interesting article from Howard
Tim Hall about 11g</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Linux cries about &amp;quot;1024 cylinders thing&amp;quot; at the time of installation&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/09/why-linux-cries-about-1024-cylinders-thing-at-the-time-of-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 21:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/09/why-linux-cries-about-1024-cylinders-thing-at-the-time-of-installation/</guid>
      <description>I have been installing Linux for last 6 years and for more than half the number of times, came across a message something like “This partitions is beyond the 1024 cylinder boundary and may not be bootable”. But never cared for it much and understood what exactly it meant to say ?
Yesterday I was reading System Admin guide to Linux by Lars Wirzenius (Thanks Howard for the link 🙂 From there I came to know what exactly that message meant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugged-in back to www&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/08/plugged-in-back-to-www/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 23:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/08/08/plugged-in-back-to-www/</guid>
      <description>Last to last week, we shifted to a new house. As there was no internet connection, so we were without any internet access for last 2 weeks. Today we got the new internet connection. Its a DSL one. And the guy who came to do the installation threw a little bit of technical jargon like rebooting the router and so on.
It feels so good to be back in the world of www 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving datafiles,control files and log files-2</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2007 19:06:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p30/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I discussed about moving datafiles. But if we want to move control files and redo files also, then the scenario is bit different. Lets see an example of the same. The current scenario is as follows:
SQL&amp;gt; select * from v$logfile;GROUP# STATUS TYPE MEMBER---------- ------- ------- ------------------------------------ 3 STALE ONLINE C:\ORACLE\ORADATA\ORCL1\REDO03.LOG 2 ONLINE C:\ORACLE\ORADATA\ORCL1\REDO02.LOG 1 ONLINE C:\ORACLE\ORADATA\ORCL1\REDO01.LOG SQL&amp;gt; select * from v$controlfile; STATUS NAME------- -------------------------------------------------------C:\ORACLE\ORADATA\ORCL1\CONTROL01.CTLC:\ORACLE\ORADATA\ORCL1\CONTROL02.CTLC:\ORACLE\ORADATA\ORCL1\CONTROL03.CTL SQL&amp;gt; select tablespace_name,file_name from dba_data_files; TABLESPACE_NAME FILE_NAME------------------------------ --------------------------------------SYSTEM C:\ORACLE\ORADATA\ORCL1\SYSTEM01.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving datafiles,control files and log files &amp;#8211; Part 1</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/21/moving-datafilescontrol-files-and-log-files-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2007 13:44:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/21/moving-datafilescontrol-files-and-log-files-1/</guid>
      <description>Many times you need to move datafiles from one location to another. The simplest approach for this is to take the tablespace offline, copy the datafiles to new location, rename the files with alter database rename file (Except that you dont have to move the SYSTEM and UNDO tablespace, as you can’t take SYSTEM tablespace offline)
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: css; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; SYS@orcl AS SYSDBA&amp;gt; alter tablespace system offline; alter tablespace system offline * ERROR at line 1: ORA-01541: system tablespace cannot be brought offline; shut down if necessary SYS@orcl AS SYSDBA&amp;gt; Well lets try moving USERS tablespace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch file for ftp&amp;#8217;ing files&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/16/batch-file-for-ftping-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 21:54:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/16/batch-file-for-ftping-files/</guid>
      <description>Today I came across a requirement where users needed to ftp files time and again. So ftp’ing again and again is not a very good option. I wrote a small batch file for the same. Just sharing the same over here. I created a folder ftp in C drive and a file get_file.bat
Contents of get_file.bat are:
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: css; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; set /p file_name=Enter the name of the file you want to ftp: echo oracle&amp;gt;c:\ftp\param.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import ORA-01435: user does not exist&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/14/import-ora-01435-user-does-not-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 09:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/14/import-ora-01435-user-does-not-exist/</guid>
      <description>One may encounter this error while importing from a dmp file from older versions of Oracle. Genereally this error is caused by some statement like alter session set current_schema=scott; And the simple reason is that the user scott doesn’t exist. Yesterday I came across this error. And the reason was that user was not created. As in case of import we generally create tablespaces first (by creating the DDL using option show=Y) but creation of users is done by import itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hats off&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/04/hats-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 22:31:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/07/04/hats-off/</guid>
      <description>Since I switched to this new job, my profile has changed. Here I work as a DBA. So my interaction with Oracle &amp;amp; anything related to Oracle has also increased. Started exploring Oracle related forums and websites specially OTN forums (http://forums.oracle.com) This is the only page thats almost always open on my Desktop in office &amp;amp; Laptop at home and I refresh more than my office Lotus Notes. Today I was reading APCs blog , that Jonathan Lewis has also started posting on OTN forums and being so busy man, from where he finds the time ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell script to spool a no of tables into .xls files&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/26/shell-script-to-spool-a-no-of-tables-into-xls-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2007 22:38:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/26/shell-script-to-spool-a-no-of-tables-into-xls-files/</guid>
      <description>On OTN someone asked a question that how to spool data from a table into a xls file. Spooling a single table I discussed in one of the previous posts. We can use the same approach to spool data from more than 1 table also. Well here I will do it through a shell script and assume that you have a text file having list of tables to be spooled (Even if you don’t have one, it can be easily made by spooling the names of tables into a simple text file) Here is the shell script that you can use to spool data to various xls files, table wise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is multiplication faster than division ?</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/18/is-multiplication-faster-than-division/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 23:02:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/18/is-multiplication-faster-than-division/</guid>
      <description>An interesing post by Laurent. Check out http://laurentschneider.com/wordpress/2007/06/to-divide-or-to-multiply.html
My findings on 10gR2 on Windoze XP
&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; var z number&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; var y number&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; exec :z := power(2,102)*2e-31;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;PL/SQL procedure successfully completed.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; exec :y := 1e125;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;PL/SQL procedure successfully completed.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; set timi on&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; exec while (:y&amp;gt;1e-125) loop :y:=:y/:z; end loop&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;PL/SQL procedure successfully completed.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b style=&amp;#34;color: rgb(255, 0, 0);&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Elapsed: 00:00:00.10&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; set timi off&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; print y&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; Y&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;----------&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;9.988E-126&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; exec :z := power(2,-104)*2e31;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;PL/SQL procedure successfully completed.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;SQL&amp;gt; exec :y := 1e125;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;PL/SQL procedure successfully completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spool to a .xls (excel) file&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/16/spool-to-a-xls-excel-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 00:14:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/16/spool-to-a-xls-excel-file/</guid>
      <description>A small tip, I read on OTN about spooling to a .xls (excel) file:
It goes like this
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: css; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt;set feed off markup html on spool onspool c:\salgrade.xls select * from salgrade; spool offset markup html off spool off And the xls it makes shows up like:
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;http://bp2.blogger.com/_cX21i_8-MT4/RnLaSNXaVrI/AAAAAAAAACM/nxm6jQbYTak/s1600-h/xls.JPG&amp;#34; onblur=&amp;#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img alt=&amp;#34;&amp;#34; border=&amp;#34;0&amp;#34; decoding=&amp;#34;async&amp;#34; id=&amp;#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5076359736360326834&amp;#34; src=&amp;#34;http://bp2.blogger.com/_cX21i_8-MT4/RnLaSNXaVrI/AAAAAAAAACM/nxm6jQbYTak/s320/xls.JPG&amp;#34; style=&amp;#34;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/img&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle concepts&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/13/oracle-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 22:16:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/13/oracle-concepts/</guid>
      <description>A very nice series of articles by Howard Rogers about Oracle Concepts. It includes all the basics like what a database, instance is ? Various types of files and all basic stuff. Read it here
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMPORT &amp;amp; EXPORT from/to compressed files directly&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/06/import-export-fromto-compressed-files-directly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 20:57:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/06/06/import-export-fromto-compressed-files-directly/</guid>
      <description>Well, a simple method to import(export) directly to(from) compressed files using pipes. Its for Unix based systems only, as I am not aware of any pipe type functionality in Windows. The biggest advantage is that you can save lots of space as uncompressing a file makes it almost 5 times or more. (Suppose you are uncompressing a file of 20 GB, it will make 100 GB) As a newbie I faced this problem, so thought about writing a post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burning your &amp;quot;OC&amp;quot;, whyz and howz &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/30/burning-your-oc-whyz-and-howz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 20:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/30/burning-your-oc-whyz-and-howz/</guid>
      <description>The very first question that may come to your mind is: what the heck this “OC” is ? Well if PC stands for Personal Computer then OC stands for Office Computer 😉 The story behind all this is:
One of my friend (He is working in a non-IT company) called me and asked how to burn a PC so that it no more works 🙂 Why ? because the PC they are given is too slow &amp;amp; old and thats the only way they can get a new one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom Kyte&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/22/tom-kyte/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 23:13:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/22/tom-kyte/</guid>
      <description>Well, a really old post on Google groups (uesnet:comp.databases.oracle.server). Someone posted a thread about Tom Kyte and then people responded with their thoughts (perfectly as expected). Read it here.
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run levels in *nix&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/14/run-levels-in-nix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 23:02:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/14/run-levels-in-nix/</guid>
      <description>If you are crazy@*nix, 2 really interesting posts about run levels in *nix
No runlevels?? What is the use of runlevels? Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using NTLDR to boot Linux&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/06/using-ntldr-to-boot-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 09:26:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/06/using-ntldr-to-boot-linux/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, while installing Linux, installing LILO/GRUB to MBR makes you run into loads of issues, one of the most popular being that after reboot you are not able to boot into either of the OS 😉 There is a way to use NTLDR to boot Linux, this way the MBR remains untouched and if you don’t want to see the Linux option, what you need to do is, edit your boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command line history in SQL (for Linux)&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/04/command-line-history-in-sql-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 20:35:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/05/04/command-line-history-in-sql-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>Found a very interesting article on Dizwell’s blog. It was about keeping history of the SQL commands in SQL Plus on Linux. It is almost very simple. Just need to download a small utility called rlwrap from here. Its a tar.gz file. Download it, un-tar using
&amp;lt;pre class=&amp;#34;brush: css; title: ; notranslate&amp;#34; title=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; tar -xvf rlwrap-0.28.tar.gz It will create a directory with the same name. cd to the directory and run</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading explain plan of a SQL query&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2007 09:27:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/p13/</guid>
      <description>Well, some information about how to go about generating and reading explain plan of a SQL query. Explain plan gives the information about the access path that Oracle is going to follow to execute your query [explain plan doesn’t actually execute the query, it just tells about the access path that Oracle will follow to execute the query; that too in current session, with all the current settings, it may be totally different in another session on the very same database].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilities I cant survive without&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/04/16/utilities-i-cant-survive-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 14:46:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/04/16/utilities-i-cant-survive-without/</guid>
      <description>Well, here I am listing down the important tools and utilities I seem to use on the daily basis and without them life on internet &amp;amp; laptop really seems to be stuck, sort of 🙁
1. Winamp: No need to say anything. Winamp is possibly the best and lightest mp3 (these days videos also) player. Just run Winamp in the system tray and enjoy
2. Winrar: Utility to uncompress compressed files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NO_DATA_FOUND&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/04/13/no_data_found/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 13:01:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/04/13/no_data_found/</guid>
      <description>I was going through Eddie Awad’s blog. There was one post about an article about NO_DATA_FOUND exception in Oracle. Both the posts you can find here and here. Do read. It is really interesting.
Sidhu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{ Height of } Helplessness&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/04/01/height-of-helplessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 19:11:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/04/01/height-of-helplessness/</guid>
      <description>There are times when you just can’t do anything, I repeat, you just can’t do anything. In the evening I was working on my laptop and everything was fine. Next day in the morning when I got up, switched on the laptop and clicked on IE icon, it happily gave a beautiful error message “This application failed to start because msvcrl.dll was not found. Re-installing the application may fix the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viruses, Intrusion attempts and Norton&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/25/viruses-intrusion-attempts-and-norton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2007 23:22:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/25/viruses-intrusion-attempts-and-norton/</guid>
      <description>When I got my Laptop, along with it also got Norton Internet Security and 2 months subscription for updates &amp;amp; all. Whenever I would boot up the laptop Internet Security would open the window for configuration. I kept on cancelling it for 2 weeks or so. But one fine (read not fine 🙁 day I configured it. It was very happy. Said Thank You at the end. But the best was yet to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent people, geeks and nerds&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/19/intelligent-people-geeks-and-nerds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 13:46:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/19/intelligent-people-geeks-and-nerds/</guid>
      <description>I was checking Tom Kyte’s blog. It was about an article titled A Note To Employers: 8 Things Intelligent People, Geeks and Nerds Need To Work Happily. Well first of all meaning of all three words from “define: * in Google”
1. Intelligent: having the capacity for thought and reason especially to a high degree
2. Geek: In computers and the Internet, a geekis a person who is inordinately dedicated to and involved with the technologyto the point of sometimes not appearing to be like the rest of us (non-geeks).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Linux from inside Windows&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/16/running-linux-from-inside-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2007 00:44:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/16/running-linux-from-inside-windows/</guid>
      <description>Running Linux from right inside Windows, just like a normal application !!! Idea looks cool. I was also searching for the same thing. After little bit of Googling got one link http://www.lifehack.org/articles/technology/beginners-guide-run-linux-like-any-other-program-in-windows.html This article explains everything about making it possible. (Thanks Kyle Pott 🙂
I had downloaded Fedore Core 7 Live CD. Tried same with this method. It is working perfectly fine. Rocking Infact !!! I have 1 Gigs of RAM in my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS Feeds&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/14/rss-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 12:47:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2007/03/14/rss-feeds/</guid>
      <description>For the last 4-5 months I was almost without a PC and internet. This problem was solved when I got my HP laptop last month and then internet connection this month. One thing I had heard much about was RSS feeds and also wanted to try the same because there were many blogs which I used to check regularly. I had an idea about the concept used by RSS feeds that you will need to install a piece of software on your PC, give link of the page you want it to monitor and it will inform you when there is something new since your last visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small things&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2006/09/27/small-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2006 16:18:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/2006/09/27/small-things/</guid>
      <description>sometimes even very small things mess up everything in your head…something similar happened with me also…had two lists of numbers…some numbers were missing in one…wanted to find out thoes..instead of inserting values in tables then using SQL or using diff on Unix…thought about using Excel for the same…much heard about function VLOOKUP is there…which we can use for such scenarios…so I also tried the same….had heard a lot abt vlookup but was generally heard of it…as when people used to write “=vlookup(bla bla bla bla…)”…i just used to count my heartbeat…and look around…so this was the time when i really needed to learn vlookup so as a normal computer geek wud do…i opened google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small things&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/small-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2006 16:18:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amardeep-sidhu.github.io/quickstart2/posts/small-things/</guid>
      <description>sometimes even very small things mess up everything in your head…something similar happened with me also…had two lists of numbers…some numbers were missing in one…wanted to find out thoes..instead of inserting values in tables then using SQL or using diff on Unix…thought about using Excel for the same…much heard about function VLOOKUP is there…which we can use for such scenarios…so I also tried the same….had heard a lot abt vlookup but was generally heard of it…as when people used to write “=vlookup(bla bla bla bla…)”…i just used to count my heartbeat…and look around…so this was the time when i really needed to learn vlookup so as a normal computer geek wud do…i opened google.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
